# Olha Klymas

+1 403 399 1831; <a href="mailto:olhaklymas@gmail.com">olhaklymas@gmail.com</a>; <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/olha-klymas-6182a415b">linkedin.com/in/olha-klymas-6182a415b</a>; <a href="mailto:Portfolio">Portfolio</a> - <a href="mailto:olhaklymas.com">olhaklymas.com</a>; <a href="mailto:GitHub">GitHub</a> - <a href="mailto:https://github.com/OlhaKlymas">https://github.com/OlhaKlymas</a>

Innovative Front End Developer with 5 years of experience building and maintaining responsive websites in a different types of industries. Have got strong skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and TypeScript; plus modern libraries and frameworks. Experienced working with the VUE framework, and know REACT. There are many sites that developed based on WordPress. Working on SalesForce Commerce Cloud (Demandware) projects and have experience with Storefront Reference Architecture (SFRA). Languages: English and Ukrainian.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

HTML, CSS, SCSS (SASS), JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React, Redux, Webpack, Gulp, Bootstrap, WordPress, Opencart, Figma, Jira, Slack.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Middle SFCC Frontend Developer | Raccoon LLC, Vinnytsia, Ukraine

04/2022 - Present

Experienced with Storefront Reference Architecture (SFRA).

The main technologies we are using are HTML, SCSS, and JavaScript (seldom jQuery).

Took part on developing several SalesForce Commerce Cloud (Demandware) projects as part of the different teams:

- updating styles for different components and pages;
- modifying and configuring content-asset assets and slots;
- setting up Page Designer pages;
- creating templates for email letters;
- writing technical documentation.

### Front End Development Teacher | IT Education Academy, Kyiv, Ukraine

10/2021 - Present

Teaching courses in HTML&CSS, JavaScript Base and JavaScript Advanced.

Have graduated more than 80 students and more of them became Junior Frontend Developers. Some students got their first work in IT during studying or the first month after the course ended.

Since last October, taking part in the project <u>IT Generation</u> of the Ministry of Digital Transformation in Ukraine and partners. It helps Ukrainians to be able to get a new qualification free. I have graduated 24 students with this project.

## Front End Developer | Sun Agency, Kyiv, Ukraine

09/2021 - 03/2022

- developed new pages on one of the popular online stores in Ukraine;
- implemented Visicom API to get customer addresses using the map;
- took participation in the development of the site using the Vue framework;
- made restyling existing pages, according to the new design in Figma.

# Front End Developer | Consult.marketing, Brovary, Ukraine

10/2018 - 09/2021

- developed various online stores and landing pages using WordPress CMS, Opencart according to the requirements;
- implemented Plektan CRM system (for realtors) via the REST API;
- used WP REST API to implement filters and post pages;
- applied different plugins to CMS WordPress like Elementor, Woocommerce, Advanced custom fields, Ajax search for woocommerce etc.

## **EDUCATION**

## National University of State Tax Service of Ukraine, Irpin, Ukraine

2011 - 2013

Master degree of Finance and credit

# IT Education Academy, Kyiv, Ukraine

2017 - 2020

Passed courses:

- HTML&CSS
- JavaScript
- Vue
- React